Microservices:
Microservices are an architectural pattern that structures an application as a collection of small, loosely coupled services that operate together to achieve a common goal. Because they work independently, they can be added, removed, or upgraded without interfering with other applications.
While there are numerous benefits to microservices architecture, like easier deployment and testing, improved productivity, flexibility, and scalability, they also pose a few disadvantages, as independently run microservices require a seamless method of communication to operate as one larger application.
Event-driven microservices allow for real-time microservices communication, enabling data to be consumed in the form of events before they’re even requested.
In this white paper, we’ll cover how event-driven microservices work, presenting a sample currency exchange platform to illustrate the design and architecture of an application composed of event-driven microservices using Apache Kafka® and Confluent Platform. We also discuss other aspects of microservices architectures, such as team structure, continuous delivery, deployment, and testing. Lastly, we discuss how Apache Kafka and Confluent Platform enable and extend core principles of microservices, including decoupling, separation of concerns, agility, and real-time streaming of event data
#
####Monolithic Services - single block of code (small E-commerce)

DockerSwarm VS Kubernetes

Docker swarm can’t to auto-scaling.
Docker swarm doesn’t have GUI. Kubernetes has GUI for monitoring but people prefer Prometheus or grafana.
Docker can reply rolling updates but can’t deploy automatic rollback.
Docker requires third party tools like ELK stack for logging and monitoring Kubernetes has some integrated tools.
Docker swarm can share storage volume with any container easliy, while Kubernetes can on share info b/w container existing in the same pod.

Heapster?
Let us do container cluster monitoring  has native support for Kubernetes.

Kubelet?
Its a service agent that helps in control and manage pods by watching for pods specs through Kubernetes API.
It runs on each node.
It maintains communication of master and node.

Kubectl?
Cmd	line tool(CLI).
Any interactions on cluster is done through Kubectl.

Different services in Kubernetes?
	ClusterIP service - default service- it is not possible to expose to browser. It gets random port
	Node Port Service - using static port service is exposed to browser.
	External Name
	Load Balancer Service - It uses load Balancer of cloud provider to expose. It basically routes nodePort and cluster IP service .

ETCD?
Key-value store having meta data, configuration data and allows nodes in cluster to read and write data.
Used for state management and cluster coordination in k8s.

Persistant Volume?

How to deploy a feature in k8s with zero downtimes?
	Deployment file -> strategy -> rolling updates

Headless Service? 
 	It enables us to reach directly to pods without need of accessing through proxy.

PVC? Persistant volume claims?
	Its storage requested by Kubernetes for pods. 
	The user doesn’t need to know underlying provision in the claim.
	The claim should be created in the same name space where the pod is created.

Secrets?
	We can pass sensitive information through it.
	It can be created through yaml or text files.
	Majority of information orgs. use secrets to pass sensitive information like username and passwords.

Sematext Docker Agent?
	It is a log collection agent with event and metrics.
	It is basically a small container in each docker-host.
	The agent gathers metrics, events and logs for all cluster nodes and containers.



