Jenkins 
	-java application
	- used for CI/CD

Download jenkins.war from official site
	- goto jenkins folder : java -jar jenkins.war
	- to integrate port : java -jar jenkins.war -httpPort=9090 default server for jenkins is jetty on which projects are deployed.
	- copy admin passwd
	- goto browser : http://localhost:8080
	- install required plugins
	- build test jobs
	- to restart jenkins from console:  http://localhost:8080/restart

Setup with tomcat: #not mandatory but its most common
	- make files +x in tomcat bin
	- start tomcat and access from : http://localhost:8080 it will close jenkins which already running
	- to access jenkins through tomcat: copy jenkins files in webapps folder of tomcat and access from url http://localhost:8080/jenkins now jenkins is integrated with tomcat

Setup home directory in jenkins	
	- check home directory default path from manage jenkins or path where installed
	- create folder of new path to be set
	- copy all data from old to new path
	- change env variable - JENKINS_HOME to new directory

Jenkins CLI:
	- advantages: easier , faster, memory management, CI 
	- start jenkins goto Manage Jenkins -> Configure Global Security -> Enable Security
	- http://localhost:8080/cli
	- download jenkins cli jar
	- java -jar full path

How to create	 Users + Manage + Assign Roles
	- Create users: goto Manage Jenkins -> Create Users
	- Configure Users: login userOne -> top right corner dropdown -> Configure 
	- Create and Manage user Roles: Role-based Authorization Strategy Plugin - download/install and restart jenkins
	- Manage Jenkins -> Configure Global Security -> Enable Security there should be new option Role based strategy 
	- Manage Jenkins -> Manage and assign roles 

Getting started with Jobs
	- how to trigger job remotely : http://jenkinsIP/TOKEN_NAME=key_used_in_configuration
	- how to chain job executions.

GIT Configuration
	- make basic java program
	- add compile and execute cmd in Jenkins shell execute : cd path; javac Helloworld.java; have Hello;
	- build in jenkins
	- add your code to git 
	- goto project location where code present: 
		git init
		git status
		git add .
		git commit -m “adding helloworld program”
		git remote add origin repo address
		git push -u origin master
