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
Jenkins 
	-java application
	- used for CI/CD

Download jenkins.war from official site
	- goto jenkins folder : java -jar jenkins.war
	- to integrate port : java -jar jenkins.war -httpPort=9090 default server for jenkins is jetty on which projects are deployed.
	- copy admin passwd
	- goto browser : http://localhost:8080
	- install required plugins
	- build test jobs
	- to restart jenkins from console:  http://localhost:8080/restart

Setup with tomcat: #not mandatory but its most common
	- make files +x in tomcat bin
	- start tomcat and access from : http://localhost:8080 it will close jenkins which already running
	- to access jenkins through tomcat: copy jenkins files in webapps folder of tomcat and access from url http://localhost:8080/jenkins now jenkins is integrated with tomcat

Setup home directory in jenkins	
	- check home directory default path from manage jenkins or path where installed
	- create folder of new path to be set
	- copy all data from old to new path
	- change env variable - JENKINS_HOME to new directory

Jenkins CLI:
	- advantages: easier , faster, memory management, CI 
	- start jenkins goto Manage Jenkins -> Configure Global Security -> Enable Security
	- http://localhost:8080/cli
	- download jenkins cli jar
	- java -jar full path

How to create	 Users + Manage + Assign Roles
	- Create users: goto Manage Jenkins -> Create Users
	- Configure Users: login userOne -> top right corner dropdown -> Configure 
	- Create and Manage user Roles: Role-based Authorization Strategy Plugin - download/install and restart jenkins
	- Manage Jenkins -> Configure Global Security -> Enable Security there should be new option Role based strategy 
	- Manage Jenkins -> Manage and assign roles 

Getting started with Jobs
	- how to trigger job remotely : http://jenkinsIP/TOKEN_NAME=key_used_in_configuration
	- how to chain job executions.

GIT Configuration
	- make basic java program
	- add compile and execute cmd in Jenkins shell execute : cd path; javac Helloworld.java; have Hello;
	- build in jenkins
	- add your code to git 
	- goto project location where code present: 
		git init
		git status
		git add .
		git commit -m “adding helloworld program”
		git remote add origin repo address
		git push -u origin master

CATLIGHT
	-  Download and run
	- used for notifications	

CI/CD
	1- build
	2- Deploy
	3- Test
	4- Release

Email Notification
	configure systems ->
	for gmail: smtp.gmail.com 
			advanced use authentication	- user passwd 
			use SSL
			port 465 (most probably)
There are other plugins also for emails and notification

Blue Ocean plugin provide cleaner view needs 2.7plus jenkins version
Poll mailbox trigger plugin : used to trigger build through mail
Build monitor plugin